待續條例草案交由內務委員會處理，環境局局長。
主席，我動議第二讀《廢物促進及妥善處理產品容器條例》2015，以修訂《產品等量責任條例》及《廢物處理條例》，就實施生產者責任制度於玻璃飲料容器。在2013，環境局。
Published the blueprint for sustainable use of resources, setting the target of reducing our per capita municipal solid waste disposal by forty percent by two thousand and twenty-two. Amongst other things, we have committed to drive behavioural change through policies and legislation, including the introduction of MSW charging and PRS, in order.
要減少廢物在源頭，一數。數項這樣的措施已經在過去一年中取得不錯的進展。例如，環保署於去年12月發表了報告，提出建議，關於如何實施量度式廢物收費。在香港，我們已經開始準備工作。塑料購物袋
Has been extended to the entire retail sector in Hong Kong, with effect from 1 April this year.
立法會批准了今年二月的撥款，用於發展廢棄電子設備處理及回收設施。在EcoPark，該設施將支援未來實施廢棄電子設備回收計劃。我們隨後引入了一項法案，進入立法。
在議會在3月2015，和法案現在正在審查委員會的審查。
The current amendment bill will further expand the PRS system, thus paving the way for the implementation of quantity-based MSW charging.
玻璃瓶裝飲料容器是適合回收和再利用。然而，我們首先需要創造一個循環經濟，使得有實用的解決方案在資源分離、收集物流、適當處理和回收渠道方面。過去的實務經驗顯示，這將會是困難的。
to arrange for effective collection of waste glass containers and turn them into resources by relying solely on market forces. This is mainly because the commercial value of glass is low, while the logistics cost is high, and there are only limited recovery outlets locally in Hong Kong. Due to these constraints, the major
Majority of the waste glass containers generated in Hong Kong are disposed of at landfills. They constitute about 2.7% of our daily MSW disposal.
With a mandatory PRS, we will have aligned statutory and administrative measures to create a circular economy for glass beverage containers.
我將解釋，Mr. President，的關鍵特徵。
We propose the legislation to first target beverage held in glass containers. This is referred to as regulated articles in the bill. We generate about 286 tonnes of waste glass containers in Hong Kong every day, of which about 194 tonnes are glass beverage containers.
85噸是玻璃食物或醬料容器，和7噸是其他玻璃容器。
We propose a phased approach to first target glass beverage bottles.
If we include other types of glass containers, commonly bought household items would be included, and this may lead to potential livelihood concern.
瓶裝容器也較容易處理，它們可以直接倒空。玻璃容器裝食物和餐具較難清潔。
如果他們 not properly cleansed， it may undermine the recycling process.
That said, the amendment bill provides a framework facilitating our review of future extension to cover other product containers.
at the same time, we will continue with public education to promote clean recycling.
我們會繼續接受所有類型的妥善清洗的玻璃容器，包括食物或醬料容器。
As required under the Product Eco Responsibility Ordinance, PRSSs must be implemented based on the polluter pays principle. Hence, we propose to collect a recycling levy from suppliers who distribute or consume regulated articles in Hong Kong. Exports or re-exports will not be subject to levy.
我們將透過補助法例規定收費水平，並考慮政府在推行PRS時所產生的全部成本。
We also propose a levy collection mechanism. First, the relevant manufacturers and importers must be registered as registered suppliers.
They have to submit periodic returns, setting out the necessary information for the computation of the recycling levy, and pay the levy. The registered supplier will also have to engage an independent auditor to conduct annual audits on the periodic returns to ensure factual accuracy.
and to keep records to facilitate future inspection.
我們將繼續密切 engage 相關貿易，進一步討論運作細節，which 將會由補助法例規定，要被引入後，經議會通過修訂法案。
現時，一小數供應商有其自己的回收安排，以收集玻璃飲料瓶供再用。我們建議提供豁免機制給這些供應商，以鼓勵繼續這些安排。我們亦建議機制應由監察及審計。
系統， to ensure the glass beverage containers are recovered. For instance, we will require registered suppliers to submit detailed plans when applying for exemption.
政府將用徵收的税款聘請數家玻璃管理承包商，透過公開招標，收集廢玻璃容器於當地社區，以便於處理及再利用。我們建議實施許可制度，以加強對儲存、處理及再製的管制。
和回收的容器廢棄物。
at the same time, we propose to require a permit for the import and export on container waste.
In order for the PRS to turn waste glass containers into a resource, there must be successful implementation of three complementary measures. First, there must be suitable recycling hardware at the community level. In the past two years, we have made good progress in setting up glass container collection points.
約1,200個住宅收集點已設立，覆蓋約69%的人口。
我們也有500個收集點，在其他場所和公共地方。
作為 hospitality trades， are the major producers of glass waste containers。我們將會step up our collaboration with them。
第二，ly， there must be suitable incentives for the PRS to work well. At present, there are various voluntary recycling programmes. We will consolidate their experience and consider how to apply effective measures more widely.
looking ahead, when quantity-based MSW charging is implemented, the pay-as-you-throw principle will create direct economic incentive for the segregation of glass containers from other waste.
第三ly， there must be adequate recovery outlets for the recovered glass materials. At present, waste glass containers are mainly crushed into cullets for use as construction materials， such as for the production of eco pavers and partition bricks. Some public works projects have also adopted recycle
玻璃材料作為填。
The construction industry is exploring the feasibility of using glass cullet to substitute river sand.
Some recyclers have also indicated that there are export markets. Taken altogether, there are sustainable outlets for recycled glass materials.
在April， we presented the latest development to the panel on environmental affairs. We look forward to explaining further to members at the Bills committee stage. While the amendment bill is under scrutiny, we will in parallel take forward other preparatory work， including further expansion of the collection network， preparation of the
Open tenders for the glass management contractor contracts and publicity and public education. We hope that the PRS will be fully implemented as soon as practicable. With these remarks, I move the motion.
現在各位提出嘅待議議題係二零一五年促進循環再造及妥善處置產品容器修訂條例草案，予二讀。咁按照議事規則，辯論已在中止待續，條例草案亦都係交由內務委員會處理。
本會現在恢復特別假期，二零一五年九月三。